Servant x Service Eps2
あれ
ミヨシさん、いないのか？
ミヨシさん、何してるんですか
あ、いや、あのう
すみません。これには訳が、、、
いた、いた
サヤちゃんもう聞いて頂戴。うちの嫁がね、、、
一度、お年寄りの方に捕まると
数時間世間話になってしまい
それで、凄く申し訳ないのですが、ちょっと隠れさせて頂いて
でもかくれてたら事務仕事もできないよね
ミヨシさん
ごめん
イチミヤさん、ミヨシさんが凹んでしまいました
何とかして、先輩
う、うん
いや、ミヨシさんは新人としては、普通の部類に入ると思うけど
その調子です
先輩、良い感じ
ほ、本当？よし
君はよくやっているよ
今年の新人は凄いよ
ヤマガミさんはバーとガーと要領よくできてるし
ハサべに至っては、すでに、上司の俺より仕事できるからな
イチミヤさんまで凹まないで下さい
私のことですみなせん、皆さん
私もいい加減ちゃんとしないといけませんね
あ、あ
はい、もしもし
はい、分かりました
ミヨシさん、大丈夫でしょうか
まあ、同じ新人でどうせのルーシーがバリバリ働いていて
プレッシャーなんじゃない？
そんなつもりはないんですけど
つもりはなくてもさ
そうだ。なんか私もまだまだ的なアッピールをさり気なくしたら？
例えば
そうだな。書類ぶちまけて
「キャー、ルーシードジしちゃった」とかさ
あっ、あは
それでも、「ルーシーこんな難しいことできません」
「助けて、ハセベ様」とか言ってみたり
それは死んでも断ります
ルーシーは薄情だな。ミヨシちゃんのためだぞ
あっ、分かりました
ど、ドジちゃった
ちょっ、ちょっと
写メ撮らないでください
安心しろ、ムービーだ
むしはもっと安心できません
ちょっちょっと
ハセベさんじゃ相談にならないよ
そうだ。チハヤさんに相談してみよう
あのう、チハヤさん、ちょっといいですか
えっ、あの
ヤマガミさん、どうしました
なるほど、それは確かに心配ですね
私も少し考えておきます
ありがとうございます
それはそうと、ヤマガミさん
明日用事があって休むので
私の仕事色々お願いして良いですか
はい、分かりました
何の用事ですか
なんか楽しそうだ
今日はミヨシさん大丈夫かな
いや、ミヨシさんの事も大したけど、
今日はいないチハヤさんの分も頑張らないと
ヤマガミさん
あれ、チハヤっ
チっ、チハヤさん
どうしたんですか
倉庫のかぎ間違って持って帰ちゃって
使うだろうから渡しておきます
あの、ええとですね
では
待って、何があったんですか、チハヤさん
チハヤじゃないわ
マジカルフラワーガーベラピンクよ
すみません
いいえ、あの、用事ってこれだったんですね
はい、本当はマナー違反なのですが会場がここから近かった物で
レイヤーんの集まるとかイベントって結構あるんです
だから私、コスプレ続けるために、休みの取りやすい臨時職員なんですよ
Temporary?
That's right. I didn't take the civil
servant's test, so my term is limited.
I'm pretty much an "irregular" staff member.
When you say "irregular"
looking like that,
it takes on an entirely
different connotation...
Long live temp employees!
Are you interested in this?
No... it's just that I've never
seen a book like that before...
If you'd like, I'll let you borrow them.
Thank you very much...
So, this is like where you make
your own book to sell it?
I've seen that on TV before.
Doki Doki Flowers
It's something like that.
A lot of civil servants make doujinshi.
We easily get vacation time
for Obon and New Year's,
so this country definitely supports otaku.
I feel like this country
has some issues, but...
Oh, what is this? A Manga Club?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll clean this up right away.
It's okay. Let me see...
Is this what I think it is?
Yes,
Itemaiya!
it's an anime currently popular
with girls called Magical Flowers!
Wow...
I know that title.
It's also a game, isn't it?
Wow, you know quite a bit.
Yeah, I play lots of games.
FF, DQ, Pokimon,
Mariko Kart, Dokimemo,
AER, Fete, etc.
You play all kinds,
not that I'm familiar with them...
I play everything.
There were some adult titles in there...
Chihaya-san?
What's up?
Civil servants aren't allowed
to dress flamboyantly,
so is that a bit frustrating for you?
Cosplay isn't only about being flamboyant.
For example, this is a civil
servant cosplay for me.
Civil servant cosplay?!
Nurses and office ladies are
a part of cosplay, too.
So in a way, Yamagami-san,
you're doing a civil servant
cosplay, too, right now.
What?
I feel embarrassed all of a sudden...
Then take off your clothes and
stop doing cosplay right now!
What?
Oh, right...
Are you an idiot?!
You weren't fooled...
Of course not!
Even putting cosplay aside,
you dress quite plainly, Yamagami-san.
Oh... Well, I'm not really
all that interested in clothes.
I think black is generic, so it's safe.
Black... I see...
Even if I got into fashion,
I wouldn't look good in anything I wore.
Even these clothes are a waste...
Since they're a waste, take 'em off.
Shut up!
Yes, regarding that matter...
Then, I'll leave it to you.
Okay.
What is it?
Yamagami-san, is it really not that
you aren't interested in clothes,
but that you can't find the
clothes that fit you...
Because of your breasts...
No! Mine might be big for my height
but they're nothing special...
F cup!
D-Do they look that small?
Thank goodness...
F is small? What the heck?
Anyway... clothes are
important for professionals.
You have to give them more thought.
You're right...
So, Yamagami-san, let's do
some anime character cosplay.
Why?!
Once you experience it,
you can wear anything.
That's too much experience for me!
I always thought you would
look good as Rose Black.
R-Rose Black?
Magical Flowers
She's a friend of Gerbera Pink.
N-No way! I couldn't wear such an outfit!
It's all right.
Rose Black represents black,
as her name suggests.
The safe, generic black, like you said.
Even though this one
shows the most skin...
Black might be okay... but
please, let me think about it.
I see...
Well, I know about clothes
more than most people,
so please, let me help you.
I love seeing people enjoying
clothes, myself included.
I would love to see
you enjoying fashion.
Chihaya-san...
I-I will try to do my best.
I look forward to it...
Seeing you as Rose Black...
Chihaya-san...
is a such nice person.
Hey, wait a sec...
You can't just... I-I mean, I'm sorry!
What's the matter?
Were you scolded, Senpai?
Did some of our citizens scold you?
She's coming...
Everyone... prepare yourselves...
The nuisance is coming...
Nuisance?
You call me, a law abiding
citizen, a nuisance?
You public servant!
It's a high school girl!
It is a high school girl!
She's a high school girl!
That's Toko-sama!
Toko-sama!
S-Sama?
So, Senpai, who is this
high school girl?
She's a regular here...
a health welfare nut.
I'm not a nut!
I-I'm sorry!
I've been coming here
to do the health and welfare
paperwork for my family.
Memorizing welfare laws is my hobby.
Nice to meet you folks!
Now I will administer a test
for you new employees
to see if you were able
capable of your jobs.
What?
U-Um... Why...
Because I'll be in trouble if
you can't do your job!
What did you mean by "test"...
I'll just have you act like
you're at the customer counter
and I'll see if you can
properly do the paperwork.
A little too much time
on your hands, Toko-chan?
Shut up! I'm offering to ascertain if you're
able to serve the citizens as a
legitimate civil servant.
Okay, I got it. Let's do the test!
T-Try not to provoke her too much, she's scary.
Scary?
She knows way more than most professionals.
So if you're not on your guard...
By the way, since
you confused "nursing senior welfare facility"
and "nursing senior insurance facility,"
how can you be expected
to teach the newcomers?
Are you stupid?
Are you just going to die?
As you can see, she rips apart your soul,
so you have to be careful...
Hang in there, Ichimiya-san!
Then I'll go first!
So you're going first? Then—
Toko-chan, which high school do you go to?
Which year are you in?
Do you have a boyfriend?
Do you have a lot of friends?
Will you introduce them to me?
Wait a sec! Let me speak!
Why are you making her mad?
Then, how about this?
If I can answer your question,
give me your email address.
Huh?
Come on, is it a deal?
Okay, but if you get it wrong,
you'd better watch out.
Sure!
What is article 78 section 7
of the nursing insurance law?
As designated by article 42
section 2's first clause,
a person conducting business related to
senior nursing living facilities
and their caregivers
may resign from the position with at least one month's prior notice.
I got a high school girl's email address!
It's hard to tell if he's smart
or just plain dumb...
N-Not bad...
All right, you're next.
You will do the simulation test.
O-Okay?
Pretend that I'm a client
that came to your counter.
Well... then please
fill out this form...
Um, please don't get too angry...
If you don't do anything weird,
I won't get mad at you.
If you scold me... I... I...
I said I'm not mad!
U-Um, uh... well...
What?
Why don't you make yourself
a little more clear?
Why're you being so mean to Saya-chan?!
Tanaka-san (76)
Wh-What?!
Who do you think you are?
Not to mention, you're wearing
such a short skirt.
What will you do if your
lower body gets cold?
My son's wife is just like you,
showing off her legs... I'm so ashamed!
Um... Please don't be so mad at her.
Next!
I'm sorry...
Well, I'll do my best, so...
You seem normal. What's your name?
Huh?
Your name. I wouldn't
mind remembering it.
Y-Yamagami Lucy Kimiko Akie
Airi Shiori Rinne Yoshiho—
Quit screwing around!
Jeez! What's with
this year's newcomers?!
Hitting on a girl,
summoning an old lady,
having some ridiculous name!
You'd better educate them properly!
C-Calm down...
At this rate, you're going to disturb everyone.
She hugged him!
Calm down, Toko!
Calling a high school girl
by just her first name?
Here you go, Toko, a welfare guide...
I have this month's newsletter, too
Ooh! I'll read.
I'll give you some allowance,
so go get some cake
and read it at home.
Yay!
He gave her money!
He gave money to a high school girl!
Be careful on your way home.
Crap! Both the citizens and my
protégés are giving me an icy stare!
He was hugged by a high school
girl and even gave her money!
Ichimiya-san, you're so vulgar!
No! I'm her—
Toko Ichimiya...
Oh, this is the application
form from earlier...
That girl's last name is...
Toko Ichimiya...
Ichimiya...
I'm her unreliable brother...
What?!
Oh, they're just brother and sister...
Causing a scene like that...
People tell us that
we don't look alike.
Senpai, why did Toko-chan
turn out that way?
She wasn't always like that...
Hurry up with my snack!
Give it to me now!
You suck at doing my hair!
Stupid! Stupid!
Sorry, she's always been like that...
Ichimiya-san, you apologize too much!
The reason she became interested
in the ward office was...
Onii-chan, what's that building?
Oh, that's a ward office.
That's where they help
people who are in trouble.
They help people in trouble?
Yeah, let's see...
they consult with you
on various issues, too.
Speaking of which,
I'm considering working there, Toko.
While I'm at work, you'll be home alone,
but you're responsible and
you'll be okay on your own, right?
Besides, you don't like me all that much...
Perhaps it's better if I'm not around.
A few days after I said that to her...
I'm home.
Oh, welcome home, Toko.
Where have you been?
I was at the ward office.
The ward office? Why?
People at the Health and Welfare
Division taught me a lot!
Apparently, we can get
quite a bit of money
if we ask for mother
and child assistance
or high-priced medical
or nursing services...
But we haven't applied for anything!
S-Sorry...
And you!
Y-Yes?!
You're only gonna make
chump change working part-time.
You need to become a civil servant
right after high school.
It's a good, reasonable job because
the income and work hours are steady.
I-I see...
S-So you stay home and study!
Ever since then, she's loved
the ward office...
No... it's not the ward office she loves.
I came for you again today!
What happened to school?
I was bored, so I just stopped by!
So it's not about the ward office
or the welfare matters...
Hey! Why are you staring off into space?
Oh... I'm sorry.
You make your living off of our
tax money, so get your act together!
You're causing problems for the people and your senpai, who's my bro—
My brother...
You like your brother, huh?
Hey! You think it's funny?!
No...
You're working right now,
so get your act together!
Come on, Toko...
I see...
this does affect the job.
Lunch Break Special Meeting
What to do about Miyoshi-san.
So we're going to have a meeting.
A random meeting has begun...
Some clients request
the impossible,
so you have to learn to draw the line.
I know, but I tend to say too much,
so now I have a habit of
holding back what I want to say.
I got it.
Since you want to change
yourself, you should try
"Blue Hydrangea" cosplay!
Chihaya-san, leave the
cosplay out of this.
Then this calls for drastic measures.
Drastic measures?
If that's the case,
I wouldn't mind cooperating.
Toko-san...
That's the spirit, because in the end,
it's for your beloved brother.
Shut your mouth, Chihaya.
Do you think it will work out?
She'll be fine. She won't
be easily discouraged.
Well, give it to me straight,
what's on your mind.
O-Okay...
Well...
What if she gets
mad or I hurt her...
But she said she'd cooperate...
But...
Spit it out already!
She got mad before she said anything!
Don't you have any pride?
Don't you have anything to say?!
Miyoshi-san, do it!
Just say a little bit!
She's right. Like, "You're just causing
trouble, so leave, Tsundere."
Shut up, Chihaya!
Um, Toko-san...
What?!
I learn a lot when you
come to the ward office a lot
and I don't mind, but it's
kind of a waste of your time,
because by doing this, your brother will
never understand your feelings...
ever...
What's going on?
What happened?
Toko?
What's wrong?
Miyoshi... She...
What did Miyoshi-san do?
Just now... she...
There's No Way She Can Say It
Damn it! Apologize!
Apologize to me!
I-I'm sorry...
She's taking her anger
out on her brother...
She's perfect for Hydrangea.
Chihaya-san, even now you're
talking about cosplay...
No, because hydrangea...
its flower meaning is "brutal."
Come on, Toko!
Cut it out!
You're being a bother!
Because of you, Miyoshi-san
cannot do her job.
Go home and watch the house, okay?
I'm gonna go... I'm not
coming back anymore...
Atta girl.
You finally understood.
I kind of feel sorry for Toko-san.
Miyoshi-san?
Wait, Toko-san!
You give me lots of
valuable information,
so please continue to educate me...
You can come anytime you'd like...
P-Perhaps every second
or third day, if possible.
Y-You've got some nerve, Miyoshi!
B-But if you insist,
I guess I don't have a choice.
I will come again!
I'll work you to the bone!
So you'd better be prepared!
Miyoshi-san is such a nice person...
But again, it doesn't help her
focus on the task at hand, either...
Picture: Nakahara Mai
U-Um... it's time for this
week's Servant Quiz again.
Our ward office is in Hokkaido, but out of
Hokkaido, Honshu, Shikoku, Kyushu...
which island uses the most shouyu (soy sauce)?
Find out the answer on our website!